[
  {
    "question": "The ICTP Ramanujan Prize is awarded annually for excellence in ______.",
    "option_1": "Chemistry",
    "option_2": "Physics",
    "option_3": "Mathematics",
    "option_4": "Biology",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first actor to win an Oscar Award?",
    "option_1": "Warner Baxter",
    "option_2": "Emil Jannings",
    "option_3": "Lionel Barrymore",
    "option_4": "Charlie Chaplin",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first Indian to win the Pulitzer Prize?",
    "option_1": "Govind Bihari Lal",
    "option_2": "Sanghamitra Kalita",
    "option_3": "Jhumpa Lahiri",
    "option_4": "Geeta Anand",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who among the following was the first non-European to receive the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1913 for his work 'Gitanjali'?",
    "option_1": "Rabindranath Tagore",
    "option_2": "Dwarkanath Tagore",
    "option_3": "Bankim Chandra Chatterjee",
    "option_4": "Abanindranath Tagore",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who among the following was the first recipient of Padma Vibhushan?",
    "option_1": "JRD Tata",
    "option_2": "Satyendra Nath Bose",
    "option_3": "Hargobind Khurana",
    "option_4": "John Mathai",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ramon Magsaysay Award was instituted in the year ______.",
    "option_1": "1957",
    "option_2": "1982",
    "option_3": "1962",
    "option_4": "1965",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year the country's highest sporting honour Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna Award was renamed as Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna Award?",
    "option_1": "1991",
    "option_2": "2019",
    "option_3": "2021",
    "option_4": "2014",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Norman Ernest Borlaug was awarded ______ in 1970 for his contribution to the green revolution.",
    "option_1": "Nobel Prize in Physics",
    "option_2": "Nobel Peace Prize",
    "option_3": "Nobel Prize in Chemistry",
    "option_4": "Nobel Prize in Physiology",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the correct statement with reference to Padma Awards.",
    "option_1": "Padma Awards can be used as suffix or prefix to the name of the awardee",
    "option_2": "Total number of Padma Awards to be given in a year should not exceed 150.",
    "option_3": "Padma Awards are given once a year.",
    "option_4": "Names of awardees are never published in the Gazette of India.",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which award was instituted by the Madhya Pradesh government in the year 1980 for exponents of Hindustani classical music?",
    "option_1": "Kumar Gandharva Samman",
    "option_2": "Tansen Samman",
    "option_3": "Kishore Kumar Samman",
    "option_4": "Iqbal Samman",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Guru Gangadhar Pradhan Award is given in which field of arts?",
    "option_1": "Theatre",
    "option_2": "Textile Art",
    "option_3": "Dance",
    "option_4": "Painting",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following gives awards and recognition in the field of Indian dance?",
    "option_1": "INTACH",
    "option_2": "Sangeet Natak Academy",
    "option_3": "Sahitya Academy",
    "option_4": "Lalit Kala Academy",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The M.G. Sangeet Puraskar is awarded annually by which of the following states?",
    "option_1": "Mizoram",
    "option_2": "Nagaland",
    "option_3": "Manipur",
    "option_4": "Chhattisgarh",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first woman weightlifter coach to win the Dronacharya Award in 2000 was ______.",
    "option_1": "Sunita Sharma",
    "option_2": "Renu Kohli",
    "option_3": "Purnima Mahato",
    "option_4": "Hansa Sharma",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was awarded the Ashoka Chakra for his gallantry during the 26/11 Mumbai terror attacks?",
    "option_1": "Mohan Chand Sharma",
    "option_2": "Hemant Karkare",
    "option_3": "R P Dengdoh",
    "option_4": "Mohit Sharma",
    "answer": "2"
  }
]

